I think we go to the studio and work out a bit of the meaning of some of these expressions.
So hang with it
High pressure and low pressure are largely what controls our weather up here in the north.
When we say high -pressure weather during the summer then we mean simply will be
sunny and warm days while if we say low -pressure weather
well then it will be a little more varied, a little more unstable weather
where there may be sun switched with some clouds and where maybe it will
rain or a rainfall passing.
Just when it comes to clouds, we have expressions such as changing clouds and varying clouds.
This picture actually shows both.
Up here in the north we have a plot -rich cloud cover
It is then changing clouds where it is stack clouds that have been formed during the afternoon.
And when it is changing cloudy it will be quite so sunny anyway on the days.
varies during the day, it may be high cirrus clouds or low cumulus clouds
These vary both in time and space.
So we may have moments that are completely cloudy and then
That they clear up and become sunny weather.
Clouds give off rain showers and rain showers are really small rainfall areas
Then it may be that a rain shower is formed, passes over a community and dies out within 20 minutes.
But they can also be a little long lasting than that and a little varied when it comes to size.
Some are very small and some are a little bigger.
And since they are so small sometimes, it can be difficult to capture them in the forecast itself.
It may also be that the forecast says they should pass
A little else than what they really pass.
Partly high summer heat and high summer heat is that the temperature comes
reach up to 25 degrees or more during the day.
A tropical night
Yes it is that the temperature did not drop below 20 degrees during the night
So the temperature was above 20 degrees all day.
Heat wave
Yes, that is when the temperature is 25 degrees or more
for a small longer period.
Then we usually say about at least five days the temperature should reach above 25 degrees.
Iron nights, yes they are a little more common during early summer
And it is simply that we get a cold night very late into the season.